<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erik&#39;s Algorithms Study Group</title>
    <link>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Erik&#39;s Algorithms Study Group</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/media/icon_hu9005a7450fd4105d0dc0f91ff08c2551_114496_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Erik&#39;s Algorithms Study Group</title>
      <link>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;about page here, with more info&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mostafatouny.github.io/erik-alg-website/meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meetings&#34;&gt;Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Weekly Meeting: Revamping The Group &lt;em&gt;(12/03/2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@mostafatouny:7/erik-alg-weekly-12-03-2022:f&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/slide/#/2/slide/view/JV1czKqPnJutA-KrYeF1h6spV4VXJZt60k4Lvma7pM0/present/&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revamping the group, re-launching totally new activities and approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launching new activities which require minimal time, technical background, and commitment. We are going to begin with those, Then slowly endorse more collaborative activities. That, In order for everything to be clear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mostafa: I had two big false assumptions about this group, time and background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Weekly Meeting: More Courses &lt;em&gt;(26/02/2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@mostafatouny:7/erik-alg-weekly-26-02-2022:0&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/file/#/2/file/wZJk6irMDAM+qhBXgPGWX5Wp/&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address the challenges the group is facing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggest more elementary courses to pursued, and how to use the three of them simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protechthor: I do really appreciate that we can pick-up more courses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Weekly Meeting &lt;em&gt;(19/02/2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@mostafatouny:7/erik-alg-19-02-2022:0&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow-up what members have achieved of Erik&amp;rsquo;s course, and discuss their solved assignments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone expressed struggling with the course, and nearly all members couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mostafa: I am encouraged by everyone&amp;rsquo;s willingness to express her/his struggle, and to persistently learn from mistakes and improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Weekly Meeting &lt;em&gt;(12/02/2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@mostafatouny:7/erik-alg-weekly-12-02-2022:4&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical discussion, Lectures and Assignment 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casual discussion, whether the course was too difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casual discussion, Generally related to the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social, Meeting new members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ben&lt;/em&gt; introduces himself: graduated from math major, transitioned to software industry and has been working for 2 years. intersted now in theoretical computer science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;caio&lt;/em&gt; introduces himself: fresh CS alumni; currently pursuing a master in compilers; motivated to study algorithms for code optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;lucper&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;caio&lt;/em&gt; are friends and had an internships together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most members did not solve assignment 1 but they are planning for it the next week end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for most members, this course is the first time they see proofs within the context of algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ben&lt;/em&gt; initiates a discussion, simple algorithm but tricky proof
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; addressed understanding a solution, and being able to creatively come up with a new, are totally two different skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;lucper&lt;/em&gt; addresses that happens very commonly in combinatorics, A problem easily understood but very trikcy to solve it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ben&lt;/em&gt; asks whether it is a pattern for greedy algorithms to be solved by induction
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; answers when an algorithm is formulated recursively or in terms of smaller instances of the same problem, Then induction is a very likely approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;caio&lt;/em&gt; agrees what &lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; as he had a similar advice from his professor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;lucper&lt;/em&gt; pointes to algorithm design book by Kleinberg and Tardos for an alternative proof by contradiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; initaties a discussion, school systems are not the best environment for training on creatively coming up with novel ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; initaites a discussion, thinking of simpler problems or different versions as a problem solving strategy.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ben&lt;/em&gt; expresses this is his main strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;caio&lt;/em&gt; mentions a quote from how to prove it by George Polya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;lucper&lt;/em&gt; agrees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; ends up the with posing a question: If progressing slowly by thinking of related problems is our sole approach for progress, Is it possible to achieve breakthroughs or unexpected leaps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;caio&lt;/em&gt;: if you cannot solve a problem, try to think of an easier version for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;First Meeting &lt;em&gt;(05/02/2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@mostafatouny:7/erik-alg-first-meeting:e&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking, Where Members introduce themselves &lt;em&gt;(15 min)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion, On students&#39; collaboration and online communities; Their challenges and suggested solutions  &lt;em&gt;(20 min)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion, On members&#39; skills and goals, and how to leverage that for Projects and subsidy learning &lt;em&gt;(10 min)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming, Multiplayer among members &lt;em&gt;(5 min)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;members introduce themselves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;lucas&lt;/em&gt;: Brazil; Master student in computational biology; Had an unfinished grad course in algorithms; Aims for advanced topics in algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;protechthor&lt;/em&gt;: Cameron; Math+CS Undergrad; Aims for competitive programming and technical interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;salvaCasta&lt;/em&gt;: Argentina; Undergrad special degree of Engineering and CS with equivalent to a master. took a first course in algorithms. wishes to prepare for hard courses. self-studies measure theory. likes information theory and prepares for it by analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;tilde&lt;/em&gt;: Sweden; Undergrad special degree of CS and Engineering equivalent to a Master; Interested in Machine Learning; Has solid background in Algorithms and Data structures. Aims for proofs lens of algorithms; Collaborated with mechatronics and political sciences students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ashok&lt;/em&gt;: Fresh highschool alumni; Familiar with programming and done machine learning projects; Lacks advanced math and foundational algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; pointed to curious intersections between computer science and information/communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;protechthor&lt;/em&gt; expressed struggling with measure theory, as there&amp;rsquo;s no clear motivation for it; it is too way abstract. &lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; offered help through mathematical logic for appreciating rigorous approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt; addressed that members might consider practical programming side of algorithms, besides course&amp;rsquo;s main goal of proofs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ashok&lt;/em&gt; explained how Physics might contribute to computing, as processing power is physically realized through the laws of physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members talked about the first picture of a blackhole (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencenewsforstudents.org/article/black-hole-first-photo-event-horizon-telescope&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;salvaCasta&lt;/em&gt;: I love it, definitely love it. i do not study math at university. so I just buy a book and try to do every exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;salvaCasta&lt;/em&gt;: Some proofs are just very hard to come up with, but not in technical terms, but rather in creative terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt;: I am sure you will learn alot from this community, &lt;em&gt;ashok&lt;/em&gt; .. let me stress the benefit is mutual. I am going to learn from &lt;em&gt;ashok&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;mostafa&lt;/em&gt;: Eventhough &lt;em&gt;ashok&lt;/em&gt; is a fresh high school alumini, He was able to actively participate in our discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;tilde&lt;/em&gt;: A course where most of the students participated in the meeting. The teacher created an environment where you felt comfortable to ask questions, even if they felt stupid. He never disregarded those questions. He also started every lecture with a very basic down to earth explanation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Intro &lt;em&gt;(20/01/2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@mostafatouny:7/erik-alg-intro:6&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/file/#/2/file/NWIKR+KMLac2CbE4uNfEQ62S/&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate group&amp;rsquo;s pedagogy, Including motivation, goals, and activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
